It was an age of war.
Relying on his own skill only,
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man is not
a wandering samurai of today.
I'm in trouble.
Why?
Why didn't you wake me up?
What? What did you say?
What are you talking about?
You're the one who was happy
you could finally sleep in.
DEPT. CHIEF KASUMI,
ENJOY RETIREMENT!
Well, then...
I'm going out now.
I'll be back!
What am I doing?
After retiring, he lost his title
as a corporate man
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story
is about a normal 60-year-old man,
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
I'm going to yoga class.
I'll be back in the evening.
Please eat something for lunch.
Please water the flowers.
Shizuko.
WARRING STATES PERIOD
SAMURAI LEGEND
MID-DAY BEER AT A RESTAURANT
Maybe I should go out.
Hm?
Go out... but where?
It's been 15 years
since I moved to this area.
I walked to the train station
through this park...
every day.
But...
this is the first time
I've walked this slowly.
I ended up at the train station by habit.
I don't need to go to the office anymore.
Hm?
I never noticed this place
while I was on my commute.
RESTAURANT AOKI
A Japanese set-meal restaurant.
That reminds me...
I always had Set A
at the office cafeteria for lunch.
I can't eat there anymore.
Okay. I've decided where to go.
I'm going in.
Welcome.
It's like a Showa-era
Japanese restaurant.
It feels so nostalgic.
Sit wherever you'd like.
FRIED SQUID SET
FRIED MACKEREL SET
BEEF CROQUETTE SET
Here's some water.
Everyone here is working.
-Done.
-Okay.
Here you are.
The hamburger steak is coming.
I'm gonna eat.
Thanks for the meal.
-Hamburger steak, order up!
-Yes.
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
SHUMAI EGG SAUSAGE
FRIED CHICKEN
CHILI SAUCE KARAAGE
EGGPLANT BELL PEPPER
PORK SPICY MISO SET
Okay.
-Thanks for the meal.
-Thank you.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
-Can I order?
-Yes. What would you like?
The eggplant, bell pepper, and pork
with spicy miso.
Yes.
And easy on the rice.
And pickled cucumbers.
-Yes.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
-Fried mackerel.
-That will be seven dollars.
-Thank you.
-Mapo eggplant.
Yes. Thank you for the exact change.
-Karaage.
-Thank you.
Beer...
I want a drink.
Cold beer...
No.
But...
Thank you very much.
Drinking beer during the day
on a weekday isn't really...
Wait.
It doesn't matter if it's a weekday
or the weekend.
I'm not a corporate man anymore.
WE HAVE COLD BEER
I can drink whenever I want.
There is nothing to worry about.
Um... Excuse me.
I can't help feeling guilty.
I guess I'll just have water.
After 38 years, it's not so easy...
to escape from...
the working-man spirit.
If I were a samurai,
I would drink
in the middle of the day
without any guilt.
That's definitely a real samurai.
What's going on?
Miss. Sake!
Coming!
Here.
Thanks.
Drinking in the middle of the day?
He's really kicking back.
-Don't end up a failure like him.
-Right.
What's so funny?
Sake is best
in the afternoon.
Not being able to do that...
Being an employed samurai
must be tough.
You insolent bastard!
How dare you mock us?
Unacceptable!
Sorry.
Hey! Go!
We're going home!
Miss!
Good pickles.
Yes.
Delicious!
So delicious!
Okay, pork fillet katsu!
-Yeah.
-Here you go.
Thanks.
Did I just see an illusion?
No.
What I just saw was...
how I really should be.
Miss.
Beer.
Yes!
I don't need to worry
about what anyone thinks
or follow anyone.
I'm going to live how I want.
My goal from now on...
is to become like a masterless samurai.
Enjoy your drink.
Drinking beer alone...
on a weekday afternoon...
This is exactly what I wanted to do.
For the first time after retiring,
I feel like I've got
a new perspective on life!
I could get used to this.
-It's done.
-Okay.
Thank you for waiting.
Eggplant, bell pepper, and pork
with spicy miso, easy on the rice,
and pickled cucumbers.
Okay.
Thank you for the meal.
Delicious.
This is just right.
Strong flavors...
go well with beer.
Beer goes down easy
during the day.
Maybe because I'm not tired yet.
The pickles are perfect.
I should explore more.
This is what freedom means.
Excuse me.
-One more, please.
-Yes!
I did it! I did it!
My first beer in the middle of the day!
You scared me.
Where did you go?
Just around here for a bit.
Do you...
think the face is red?
I think it's red.
Really?
Well...
Actually, I...
-I just had--
-Do I...
look red?
I drank too much wine at lunch.
She beat me!
What's wrong?
Nothing's wrong.
Takeshi Kasumi.
Sixty years old.
I lost my title,
but my life...
has just begun.
Subtitle translation by
Hoday Stearns